

## **Profile**

Creative and experienced Photographer/Filmmaker with over 12 years of experience in the field of photography and 6 years of experience in E-Commerce as Photography Manager. Proven ability to lead team with the attitude of "inspire to aspire". Ability to deep dive and find solutions. Committed to learn fast changing technology and utilize my experience and knowledge to contribute to the growth of the organization. Proven ability to effectively self-manage independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting. Currently up skilling to UI/UX design.

## **Employment History**

#### Freelance / Consultant, Self, Dubai/India

JULY 2021 — PRESENT

#### Consultant - HOTPACK, Dubai

- Assessing the existing 400+ imagery to understand the bottlenecks.
- Assessment of Product Photography equipment and recommended necessary upgrade based on their requirements.
- Giving End to End 5 days training on Product Photography for the team
- Shot around 350 SKUs ranging from transparent to high gloss.
- Introduced & trained the team on Colour Correction and Image Editing.

#### Product Photography - SONASHI, Dubai

 Imaged over 500 home and kitchen appliances products r for their Ecommerce Channel.

#### Food Photography - CASINETTO, DUBAI

 Imaged over 1500 products including Dry and Frozen, for their Ecommerce Channel

### DOP - BRHAT, Hyderabad, India

• DOP for BRHAT's documentary movies on ancient temples of Karnataka. This was a 6 day program covering over 10 temples.

### Photography Manager, Amazon.ae / Souq.com, Dubai

AUGUST 2015 — JUNE 2021

## **Role and Responsibilities**

- Lead a team of 5 photographers.
- Assisted Studio Manager with all tasks related to imagery and production across 5 product bay and 2 on figure bay.
- Responsible of coordinating with the production team to ensure 100% production targets are achieved.
- Responsible for achieving quality standards of imagery with less than 1% rejection.
- Achieving 100% productivity on bay shooting of fashion and high gloss product photography.

### **Achievements**

- Increased equipment and resource utilization resulting in cost saving and increased productivity by 25%.
- · Recognized by senior leadership for creating more than 10 training

### **Details**

+91 9995009151 k.pradeep.menon@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE OF BIRTH 17/07/1976

### Links

<u>Portfolio</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> Instagram

#### **Skills**

**Fashion Photography** 

**Product Photography** 

**Image Editing** 

Videography

Microsoft Office

## Languages

English

Hindi

Malayalam

Tamil

#### **Hobbies**

Pencil Sketching, Trekking, Cooking

- videos across all product categories for global teams that helped photographers set up the station and shoot with ease. This resulted in achieving quality standards.
- Implemented PIXEL a detailed approach to imaging on figure fashion the DXB region that resulted in increased visibility and more than 30% increase in sales of fashion products.
- Worked on customer feedback mechanism that resulted in increased customer satisfaction. I was able to bring down the return rate by 40%
- Initiated research and testing of 360 degree product videography in the DXB region.

### Co-founder and Head Commercials, LUCIDA, Delhi

APRIL 2010 - MAY 2015

- Produced and filmed 18 documentary films for PHFI / Bill & Melinda
   Gates Foundation on public health.
- Recognized for providing workshops on photography for more than 75 young women belonging to underprivileged sector on women safety.
   Their work was exhibited at Alliance Francaise, Delhi.
- Exhibited my photography work at prominent art galleries and organizations like Alliance Francaise, Muxmuller Bhavan etc.
- Worked with the team in pitching the business proposal to NDBI, a
  government funding agency that resulted in receiving half a million as
  seed funding.
- Member of the editorial board of the art magazine PIXEL by Al Kazi foundation and Muxmuller Bhavan.
- Photography documentation project 'Dying textile traditions of the North East' for National Institute of Design (NID) and Government of India

#### Art Director, Quick Silver Advertising, Hyderabad

MARCH 2008 — OCTOBER 2008

- Worked on brand identity and ad campaigns for various brands like TIME Institute, NOVOTEL groups etc.
- Offered design solutions that effectively solved problems and enhanced brand visibility for clients
- Utilized crucial design software skills to assist with projects.

### Education

## PG, National Institute of Design, Ahmedabad

NOVEMBER 2008 — MAY 2010

Post Graduate Certification in Photography Design

### **GNIIT**, NIIT, Chennai

JUNE 1997 — JUNE 1999

Professional Certification for 2 years on Information Technology and Programming

### B.A., Loyola College, Chennai

JUNE 1994 — MAY 1997

Bachelor's of Arts - History

### Courses

UI/UX, UDEMY

## Realism in Pencil Sketching, Pencil Perception

AUGUST 2022 — PRESENT

## **Motion Graphics, UDEMY**

OCTOBER 2022 — PRESENT

# **Softwares Known**

Photoshop

CaptureONE

Lightroom

PremierPro

Illustrator

Indesign